lilly.com 2018-10-04

# Privacy

## Scope of this Website Privacy Statement

Eli Lilly and Company ("Lilly") has established a comprehensive privacy program, including a global privacy office and a chief privacy officer, designed to help us respect and protect your privacy rights. This statement includes the Website Privacy Statement and details regarding appropriate transfer mechanisms including the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield, and is incorporated into and made a part of our Terms of Use. If you have not done so already, please also review Lilly’s Terms of Use, which include provisions that limit Lilly’s liability to users of the services described in this statement.

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Statement is intended to let you know what information Lilly may collect about you and how we use that information. This Privacy Statement applies to websites that link to this statement when you click on "Privacy Statement" in the website footer, as well as mobile applications and digital services that link to or post this Privacy Statement. In this Privacy Statement, we will refer to the websites, Apps, and Digital Services that may link to or post this Privacy Statement as “websites.” Additionally, the Social Security Number Protection Policy stated below applies to all Lilly operations.

## Consent to Processing in the United States and Elsewhere

This site is owned and operated by Lilly in the United States, but the Personal Information (defined below) you provide may be accessible to our affiliates, vendors and suppliers in other countries. If you are visiting this site from a country other than the United States, your Personal Information collected on this site will be transferred outside of your country. The level of legal protection for Personal Information is not the same in all countries and the laws may be more protective in your country than in countries where we process your information; however, we will take reasonable efforts and security measures as described in this Privacy Statement in an effort to keep your information secure. By using this site, you consent to the collection, storage, and processing of your Personal Information in the United States and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations. In addition to its internal global privacy policies, Lilly and its affiliates in the United States adhere to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce and other appropriate frameworks regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from the European Union (EU) and Switzerland.

## Social Security Number Protection Policy

Eli Lilly and Company collects Social Security numbers and other sensitive personal information in the ordinary course of its business. Lilly has implemented reasonable technical, physical, and administrative safeguards to help protect the Social Security numbers and other sensitive personal information from unlawful use and unauthorized disclosure. All Lilly workers are required to follow these established procedures, both online and offline. In particular:

• Access to Social Security numbers is limited to those workers and service providers who have a need to access the information to perform tasks for Lilly. Social Security numbers are only disclosed to third parties in accordance with Lilly’s established privacy policy.

• We will only disclose Social Security numbers (i) with those service providers, auditors, advisors, and/or successors in interest who are legally or contractually obligated to protect them, or (ii) as required or permitted by law.

## Information We Collect and How We Use It

• Summary: This website may collect Personal Information that either directly identifies you or could be used in combination with other information to identify you. Examples of Personal Information that directly identify you include your name, contact information, email address, and other information in combination with identifiers. Our websites may also collect Personal Information that does not directly identify you by name or contact information but which may be used to identify that a specific computer or device has accessed our website. 

Through this website, we may collect the following information about you:

• Contact information: This might include information such as your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, and other similar information ("Personal Information"). We collect this information so that we can communicate with you. You may always refuse to provide Personal Information to us, but then we may not be able to provide you with certain information, products, or services.

• Additional Information: Certain areas of our Websites allow you to share additional Personal Information with us. For example, you may subscribe to one of our mailing lists or newsletters. We may use the information you provide to send your requested information, respond to your inquiry, improve our websites, verify your relationship with us, and take other actions that may be necessary to respond to your request.

• Interests and preferences: This information lets us better understand how to best serve you based on your interest in our products and services. This information may include your preferences about how to contact you, further develop a business or professional relationship, understand product preferences, languages, marketing preferences, and some demographic data. Some of this information we collect with your consent and some of this information we collect automatically for our legitimate business purposes.

• Website Usage: We use this information to manage and secure our websites, network systems, and other assets. This may include information about your IP (“Internet Protocol”) address, the date and time of your website session, geographic location, and how you have navigated the website, and other information collected through our weblogs, cookies or in other ways. This may also include information that does not directly identify you but which corresponds to your device. It is possible that your IP Address, or a cookie that we use, may contain information that may be considered Personal Information. How we use Cookies and other technologies is described in more detail below. This information is collected automatically, for our legitimate business purposes.

We may also use the information to meet legal or regulatory obligations, such as adverse event reporting or to enforce our rights; and for company record retention, website management, research and product development that are in the legitimate interest of Lilly. 

Where permitted by law, we may also enhance or merge information about you, including Personal Information, with information about you obtained from third parties for the same purposes shared above. Your information may also be used for profiling for the same purposes shared above. You may object to profiling via automated-decision making by contacting us using the information in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

## Cookies and Similar Technologies

_Web beacons_

This site may use a technology known as web beacons that allows the collection of web log information. A web beacon is a tiny graphic on a web page or in an e-mail message designed to track pages viewed or messages opened. Web log information is gathered when you visit one of our websites by the computer that hosts our website (called a "webserver"). 

On certain web pages or in emails we send to you, we may utilize a technology called a “web beacon” (also known as an “action tag” or “clear GIF technology”). We may use web beacons to help determine which email messages sent by us were opened and whether a message was acted upon. Web beacons also help analyze the effectiveness of websites by measuring the number of visitors to a site or how many visitors clicked on key elements of a site.

_Cookies_

This website may use a technology called a "cookie.” A cookie is a small data file that a website can place on your computer’s hard drive, where your internet browser files are kept. A cookie saves you the trouble of reentering certain information in some registration areas because cookies can be used to enable a site to “remember” information a visitor has previously inputted. A cookie also helps deliver content used -specific information to you and track how sections of the website are used. Cookies can be placed on your computer both by us and by third parties with whom we have a relationship, such as web analytic services and advertising network services. In addition, cookies may be used to remarket employment opportunities to you in the United States. With most Internet browsers or other software, you can change your browser settings to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please check your browser instructions to learn more about these functions. If you reject cookies, functionality of the site may be limited, and you may not be able to take advantage of many of the site's features.

_Third-Party and Digital Advertising_

We may partner with third-party advertising networks to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partners may place cookies and Web beacons and similar digital markers on your browser when you visit our websites to collect information about your activities over time on this and third-party websites, apps, and other online services, to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. We may also share Personal Information about you with third-parties in order to have those third-parties on our behalf directly serve advertising to you on their websites.

_Choices about Cookies_

If you would like to opt-out of, or manage, cookies used for targeted advertising, you may do so by following the options provided by the Network Advertising Initiative at: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> and the Digital Advertising Alliance at: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. Ads displayed to you using this technology will usually have an adchoices logo in the corner, which you can also click on to begin the same opt-out process. Additionally, if you receive ads on a social media site (such as Facebook or Instagram), you can check that site’s privacy statement and terms of use to determine how to stop seeing such ads. 

The European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance keeps a website where people can opt out of receiving interest-based advertising from some or all of the network advertising companies participating in the program. You can find information about the EIDAA here www.youronlinechoices.eu.

_Do Not Track_

There are different ways you can prevent tracking of your online activity. One of them is setting a preference in your browser that alerts websites you visit that you do not want them to collect certain information about you. This is referred to as a Do-Not-Track (“DNT”) signal. Please note that currently our websites and web-based resources do not respond to these signals from web browsers. At this time, there is no universally accepted standard for what a company should do when a DNT signal is detected.

## Reasons Your Information is Shared

We may share your Personal Information with our agents, contractors or partners in connection with work that they do for, or with, Lilly, such as sending email messages, managing data, hosting our databases, providing data processing services, providing customer service, or so we may enhance or add data about you from these other entities. These agents, contractors or partners are restricted from using this data in any way other than to provide services for us, or services for the collaboration in which they are engaged with us (for example, some of our products are developed and marketed through joint agreements with other companies).

We will share Personal Information to respond to subpoenas or other lawful information requests of governmental authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements, to provide Internet security, or where required by law. In exceptionally rare circumstances where national, state or company security is at issue, we reserves the right to share our entire database of visitors and customers with appropriate governmental authorities.

We may also provide your Personal Information to a third party in connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of the business of a website to which the information relates, in which case we will require any such buyer to agree to treat Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

## Google Analytics

Google Analytics may be used to help make our website work better and to help us understand what parts of the website are being utilized. Google Analytics uses technical tools such as, First-party cookies and JavaScript code, to collect information about visitors. Google Analytics service tracks visitors to the site who have JavaScript enabled. Google Analytics anonymously tracks how visitors interact with a website, including where they came from and what they did on a site. Google Analytics collects the information set forth above from users.

This information is used to administer and update the website, and we will also assess whether the visitors to the site match the expected site demographics and determine how key audiences are navigating the content.

First-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) will be used to report how your ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to this site.

A. Opt-Out Provision: Google analytics offers an opt-out provision for website visitors who do not want their data to be collected. You can receive more information about this option here: [](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Please note: If you click this link, you will leave this Lilly website.")<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

B. Google's Use of Data: Google and its wholly owned subsidiaries may retain and use, subject to the terms of its Privacy Policy (located at [](http://www.google.com/privacy.html "Please note: If you click this link, you will leave this Lilly website.")<http://www.google.com/privacy.html>, or such other URL as Google may provide from time to time), information collected in your use of the Google Analytics Information Disclosures and Sharing.

## Social Media Plug-ins

Our websites may use Social Media Plug-ins to enable you to easily share information with others. When you visit our websites, the operator of the social media plug-in that is on our website can place a cookie on your computer that lets that operator to recognize individuals on their website who have previously visited our sites. If you have previously logged into the social media website while browsing on our website, social media w-ins may allow that social media website to receive directly identifiable information about you that shows you have visited our website. The social media plug-in may collect this information for visitors who have logged into social networks, whether or not they specifically interact with the plug-in on our website. Social media plug-ins also allow the social media website to share information about your activities on our website with other users of their social media website. Lilly does not control any of the content from social media plug-ins. For more information about social plug-ins from social media websites, you should refer to those sites’ privacy and data sharing statements.

## How Long We Keep Your Information

Your Information will be saved for a period of time needed to fulfill legitimate and lawful business purposes in accordance with our records retention policies and applicable laws and regulations.

## Children’s Information

This site is not intended for or designed for individuals under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from any person under the age of 18.

## How We Secure Your Information

We provide reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect Personal Information collected via this website. For example, we limit access to this information to authorized employees, service providers, and contractors who need access to perform the activities described in this notice. Although we strive to provide reasonable security for information we process and maintain, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches.

## California Privacy Rights

Your Privacy Rights: California Civil Code Section 1798.83 entitles California residents who have an established business relationship with Lilly to request information regarding Lilly’s disclosure of certain Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make a request for such information, you may contact us using the information in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

## Your Rights and Choices

You have the right to request information from us on how your personal information is being used and with whom that information is being shared. You also have the right to see and get a copy of the personal information that we have about you. If you believe any of this information to be inaccurate or incomplete, you have the right to request its correction or erasure. There may be limitations on our ability to comply with your request.

## How to Contact Us

You may make any of the above requests by contacting us at: Eli Lilly and Company P.O. Box 6245 Indianapolis, IN 46206-6245 Or calling Lilly toll-free at 1-800-LillyRx (1-800-545-5979).

You may also contact us at the above if you have questions about this Privacy Statement.

## How to Submit a Complaint

If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal information, you can contact our Data Protection Officer at [privacy@lilly.com](mailto:privacy@lilly.com) who will investigate the matter.

If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are processing your personal information not in accordance with the law you can register a complaint with a Data Protection Authority (DPA).

## Links to Third-Party Websites

As a convenience to our visitors, this Website may contain links to other sites owned and operated by third parties that we believe may offer useful information. The policies and procedures we describe here do not apply to those sites. We are not responsible for the collection or use of Personal Information at any third party sites. Therefore, we disclaim any liability for any third party's use of Personal Information obtained through using the third party website. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy, security, data collection, and distribution policies.

## Transfer of Personal Information Internationally

Lilly may transmit personal information about you to other Lilly affiliates worldwide. These affiliates may in turn transmit personal information about you to other Lilly affiliates. Some of Lilly’s affiliates may be located in countries that do not ensure an adequate level of data protection. Nevertheless, all of Lilly’s affiliates are required to treat personal information in a manner consistent with this notice. To obtain additional information regarding the basis for transfers and safeguards that Lilly has in place for cross-border transfers of personal information, please contact us at privacy@lilly.com.

_EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield_

Eli Lilly and Company, including Lilly USA, LLC and Avid Radiopharmaceuticals, Inc. (“Lilly U.S.”) has elected to self-certify to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks (“Privacy Shield”) and utilizes other transfer mechanisms as appropriate. Lilly U.S. processes the Personal Information we receive in the United States from the EU, EEA and Switzerland relating to individuals that visit a Lilly website in accordance with the Privacy Shield Principles and other transfer frameworks, as applicable. If you have been directed to this Privacy Statement from a website other than Lilly.com, the information about how Lilly U.S. adheres to Privacy Shield and other transfer requirements takes precedence over any conflicting information provided in the other website privacy statement.

If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Statement and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. For Personal Information originating in the EU, EEA or Switzerland, this Privacy Statement demonstrates our commitment to processing your Personal Information in accordance with the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement, and Liability.

As explained in the Information Disclosures and Sharing section, your Personal Information may be shared as appropriate with third parties that process information on behalf of, or with, Lilly U.S. If we disclose Personal Information received under the Privacy Shield or other appropriate transfer mechanisms to a third party, Lilly U.S. ensures that the third party has contractual provisions that require the same level of security and confidentiality safeguards as required under the Privacy Shield or by the required transfer framework, as the case may be. Under certain circumstances, Lilly U.S. may remain liable for the acts of certain third parties if those third parties process the EU-, EEA- or Switzerland-originating Personal Information that Lilly discloses to them in a manner that is inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles.

As explained in the “How to Contact Us” Section, if you have any inquiries or complaints about our handling of your Personal Information under the Privacy Shield or other appropriate transfer framework, or you want to view your Personal Information that Lilly U.S. processes and request the correction, amendment or deletion of such data, please contact us by writing to:

Eli Lilly and Company P.O. Box 6245 Indianapolis, IN 46206-6245 Or calling Lilly toll-free at 1-800-LillyRx (1-800-545-5979).

If, after attempting to address privacy question or concern with Lilly U.S. directly by contacting us using the contact information listed above, you still have a specific privacy concern that has not been resolved; you may choose mediation of that concern by the neutral third party, American Arbitration Association. Submit your unresolved privacy concern to the American Arbitration Association for resolution.

American Arbitration Association Case Filing Services Toll free: 877.495.4185 Fax: 877.304.8457 [casefiling@adr.org ](https://casefiling@adr.org/ "Please note: If you click this link, you will leave this Lilly website.") [](http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html "Please note: If you click this link, you will leave this Lilly website.")<http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html>

With respect to Personal Information originating in the EU, EEA or Switzerland, you may also have the option to select binding arbitration for the resolution of your complaint under certain circumstances. For more information on binding arbitration, see US Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield Framework: Annex I (Binding Arbitration) at [](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction "Please note: If you click this link, you will leave this Lilly website.")<https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>.

For purposes of enforcing compliance with the Privacy Shield, Lilly U.S. is subject to the investigatory and enforcement authority of the US Federal Trade of Commission. For more information about the Privacy Shield and to view Lilly U.S.’s certification page, please visit the website of the US Federal Trade of Commission on Privacy Shield located at [](https://www.privacyshield.gov/ "Please note: If you click this link, you will leave this Lilly website.")[https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/ "Please note: If you click this link, you will leave this Lilly website.").

## Changes to Our Privacy Practices

We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. When we do update it, for your convenience, we will make the updated statement available on this page. We will always handle your Personal Information in accordance with the Privacy Statement in effect at the time it was collected. We will not make any materially different use or new disclosure of your Personal Information to another entity using your Personal Information for its own purposes unless we notify you and give you an opportunity to object.

Last Updated: August 20, 2018
